artrage.com 2019-12-30

# Privacy - ArtRage

### Our ethics, policies & principles

## Ambient Design Privacy Policy

 _We consider the privacy of our visitors to be extremely important._

## Who we are

Ambient Design is a New Zealand based software development company specializing in creative tools for artists. Our flagship product is ArtRage, a simple and stylish digital painting product that presents a high technology paint simulation in an easy to use interface that lets anyone play with paint, available across a range of platforms. To learn more about us: Ambient Design

 **Our website address is:** [https://www.artrage.com](https://www.artrage.com/)

## ArtRage Software

### ArtRage Desktop Editions

Versions of ArtRage that come with a Serial Number do not use DRM (Digital Rights Management), or run any kind of background services. Once you have installed one of these products, you do not need an internet connection at all, except for an optional update check that will alert you to updates if you choose. This update check does not run without prompting you for permission each time it is scheduled.

Versions of ArtRage bought from an external store that do not come with a Serial Number may use licensing services provided by the store from which the product was purchased. In these cases, Ambient Design does not gather any data and you can refer to the Privacy Policy of the store for further information.

The only additional software that may be installed with these products is a Thumbnail Viewer on Windows that allows the operating system to preview ArtRage files. This viewer does not collect or transmit any data. These versions of ArtRage do not include ads.

### ArtRage Mobile Editions

The Mobile editions of ArtRage (including ArtRage for iOS, ArtRage for Android, and some older products purchased from external stores) do not include adware or any other background services. Ambient Design does not collect any personal data or require an active internet connection to use these products. Licensing and updates are handled by the store from which the product was purchased and you can refer to the Privacy Policy for that store for further information.

## ArtRage.com, Member Area & Web Services

### What personal data we collect and why do we collect it?

The following privacy statement discloses the information gathering, what we use, and privacy protection practices of this site, [ArtRage.com](https://www.artrage.com/ "ArtRage").

### Log Files

Like many other Web sites, artrage.com makes use of log files. These files merely log visitors to the site, a standard procedure for hosting companies and a part of hosting service’s analytics. The information inside the log files includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date/time stamp, referring/exit pages, and possibly the number of clicks. This information is used to analyse trends, administer the site, track user’s movement around the site, and gather demographic information. IP addresses, and other such information are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable.

### Cookies

The artrage.com website uses cookies to store information about visitors’ preferences, to record user-specific information on which pages the site visitor accesses or visits, and to personalize or customize our web page content based upon visitors’ browser type or other information that the visitor sends via their browser.

If you wish to disable cookies, you may do so through your individual browser options. More detailed information about cookie management with specific web browsers can be found at the browsers’ respective websites. [What Are Cookies?](http://www.privacypolicyonline.com/what-are-cookies/ "What are cookies")

### Third-Party Sites and Services

The artrage.com website may contain links to third-party websites, products, widgets and services. You should consult the respective privacy policies of these third-party sites for more detailed information on their practices as well as for instructions about how to opt-out of certain practices, if desired.

 **Google Services**

The artrage.com website uses various technologies to collect and store general website usage information via Google services. Learn more about the [Google’s Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ "Google Privacy").

 **Amazon Affiliate**

Ambient Design has an affiliate relationship with the Amazon store and benefits from any purchases made on the artrage.com website through Amazon sales. Learn more about [Amazon’s Privacy](https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=468496 "Amazon Privacy").

 **Apple Software**

Ambient Design provides software for the iPad and iPhone, sold via the Apple App Store. You’ll notice that we also use iTunes affiliate links where appropriate. Rest assured, these affiliate links do not affect you in any way. They will, however, share a small portion of the sale with us. Check here for the [Apple’s Customer Privacy](https://www.apple.com/privacy/ "Apple Privacy").

 **Facebook and other social networks**

The artrage.com website links out into various social networks for the art community, such as Facebook. More information about [Facebook’s Privacy](https://www.facebook.com/help/445588775451827 "Facebook Privacy").

### Children’s Information

We believe it is important to provide added protection for children online. We encourage parents and guardians to spend time online with their children to observe, participate in and/or monitor and guide their online activity. Ambient Design does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. We advise all children to first get their parents or guardians permission before creating an account for the ArtRage Member Area and Forums.

## How we protect your data

To ensure your data is kept safe, this website is secured and encrypted privacy communications with Digicert SSL. DigiCert is the world’s premier provider of high-assurance digital certificates.

We do not sell/market data or use advertising in any of our products and on this website.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

### Consent

By using our website, you hereby consent to our privacy policy and agree to its terms.
